

34-38 42nd Street Queens, NY 11101

646.462.2714

pavluk73@gmail.com dmitrypavluk.com github.com/dmonay

Profile

Just do it. Nike's motto adeptly describes my approach to life. I learn by doing and I do by building. I work on things that excite me in the depths of my heart; work becomes play, a game that makes life meaningful and interesting.

Frontend development was my segue drug into the world of software. I have since built applications in Go, and enjoy building out the backend infrastructure for projects. I am drawn to the big picture, the high-level architecture that a company designs and employs to produce efficient and effective products. It is this desire to understand the big picture that drew me towards the backend and application programming.

I have experience building RESTful APIs via microservices and decoupled architectures.

Experience

## Backend Developer; F#; New York, NY

2015-present

Design, implement, deploy, maintain, and optimize highly available web api in Node.js. Migrate legacy services from Mongo to Postgres.

## Frontend Engineer; CrowdSurge; Brooklyn, NY

2014-2014

My responsibilities included building a point-of-sale frontend application using AngularJS. The backend consisted of a combination of new Go micro services and legacy PHP APIs that made communicating with the server interesting and challenging. Collaborated with a team in London via GitHub, HipChat, and Hangouts.

## **Product Design Track; Startup Institute; New York, NY**

2014-2014

Startup Institute is an immersive full-time professional career accelerator that helps individuals develop the mindset and skills necessary to successfully launch into a career at a startup.

Education

Johns Hopkins University; Baltimore, MD — History / premed 2013 Stuyvesant High School; New York, NY — 2009

Skills

C, Go, Node.js

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcached, RabbitMQ

Linux, Vagrant, Docker

Grunt, Bower, Jenkins, Git

Git flow, code reviews, unit testing, integration testing, agile

RESTful APIs: using, building, deploying, CI, AWS, Google Cloud

HTML, CSS/SCSS, JS, AngularJS